ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译
小酸奶!
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
电脑团
翻译
静妹粒
冬麟  累
时间轴
想念Gallifrey的Wholock
电脑狂人
第三季
第三集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
无线电收发两用机
福布斯
免费?
CQ  CQ  有人用这个频率吗
CQ, CQ, is this frequency in use?
CQ  有人吗
CQ, is anybody out there?
有人吗  我是KC4L
Hello? This is KC4L.
有人听得到吗
Can anybody hear me?
那是什么
What's that?
我自己搭的无线电
It's a radio that I made.
CQ是什么意思
What does CQ mean?
如果你要找其他搭了无线电的人
It's what you say when you're looking for other people
就要说CQ
who've made radios.
从法语词sécurité来的
Comes from the French word sécurité,
意思是安全  保障
which means safety or security.
听着和sécu差不多
You can hear it when you say "Sécu, sécu."
有什么事吗
Did you want something?
我想道晚安
I wanted to say good night.
天啊  小家伙  对不起
Oh, God, Lump, I'm so sorry.
刷牙了吗
Did you brush your teeth?
我马上就过来  好吧
Okay, I'll be out there in just a second, okay?
爸爸在橱柜里找其他用无线电的人
Daddy's in the closet looking for people with radios.
好吧
Okay.
你把那玩意从德州带来
That thing made it from Texas
却把厨宝产品留在了仓库里吗
and the KitchenAid is still in storage?
你真打算站那儿
Are you really gonna stand there
装成是会用那台搅拌机的人吗
and try and pass yourself off as someone who ever used that mixer?
你觉得这地方适合搞这些吗
Are you sure this is the best place for all this?
我相当确定这里极不适合
No, I'm pretty sure it's the worst place for it,
但既然我本来想用的地方被占了
but since the place that I was gonna use isn't available,
-就这么凑合吧  -好吧  抱歉
- I'm making do. - Okay, sorry.
找到人了吗
Have you found anyone?
没有  连接不好
No, the connection sucks.
或许是天线的问题
Is it the antenna, maybe?
我也说不准  有可能
I don't know. Could be.
也可能是我小时候
Or it could be that all the guys
那些用这个的人
that were out there when I was a kid
都忙着经营公司没时间玩无线电了
are too busy running companies to have time for hams.
嗯  或者他们改上网了
Yeah, or they moved online.
肯定还有新的发烧友
There must be some new kids out there.
我一会儿就出来
I'll be out in a sec.
CQ  CQ  我的天  有人吗
CQ, CQ, for shit's sake, is anybody out there?
卡梅伦和我决定开个每周项目会议
Hey, Cameron and I decided to have a weekly project meeting
梳理跳蚤市场的整合
to streamline the SwapMeet integration
我们认为你的参与会很有价值
and we thought that you'd be a valuable addition.
好的  没问题
Yeah, sure.
如果你希望我参与的话
If you want me there.
嗯  我们希望
Yeah, we do.
你希望我参加
Do you want me there
是因为你觉得我可能会有贡献
because you think I might have something to contribute
还是因为你想让我感觉自己有事做
or because you want me to feel like I have something to do?
只是因为我尊重你的观点呢
How about just because I respect your opinion?
因为我不想让你觉得我不能自己振作
'Cause I just don't want you to feel like I can't self-start
因为我完全可以的
because I absolutely can.
你当然可以  但程序员都依赖你
No, of course you can, but the coders look to you.
我觉得你会是条很有价值的纽带
I feel like you could be a valuable liaison.
并且我希望有你在
And I want you there.
好的  我会去的
Okay. Yeah. I'll be there.
很好
Good.
我其实没什么选择
You know I don't really have a choice.
你是我的依靠
You're my ride.
-麦克米伦先生  -莱恩  欢迎
- Mr. MacMillan. Hi. - Ryan, welcome.
我没想到这...
I didn't realize it was, you know,
会是个这么大派对  所以...
gonna be such a big party, so I...
太有心了  谢谢
That was very thoughtful. Thank you.
你家真漂亮
This is really a beautiful place you have.
光线很暗
You know, it's dark.
不太能看清楚东西
Can't really see what everything looks like,
但就我看来  这...
but from what I can tell, it's--
这很...
it's so...
亚洲风
Asian.
我很高兴你喜欢
I'm glad you like it.
嗯  我找了好久才找到
Yeah, it took me a while to find it.
这城市我不太熟
I don't really know the city that well.
我在伯林盖姆长大
I grew up in Burlingame.
那里不远
It's not far.
只是  我们不经常来城里
Just-- yeah, we didn't really get to come to the city that much.
但我真的很喜欢  看看这儿
I really do like it, though. I mean, look at it.
它真是
It's just so...
很亚洲风
Asian.
你朋友真多
You sure do have a lot of friends, huh?
我不会把这些人叫做朋友
I wouldn't really call these people my friends.
他们大多都不知道自己在谁的房子里
Most of them don't even know whose house they're at.
除了那边的肯
Except for Ken over there.
肯很清楚状况
Ken knows exactly where he is.
我渴了
You know what? I'm thirsty.
我们打开它吧
Why don't we open this up?
那你现在住在哪
So whereabouts do you live now?
还在伯林盖姆吗
Or are you still in Burlingame?
不  我搬出来有段时间了
Oh, no, I got out of there a while ago.
我现在在洛斯阿图斯和大学同学住一起
I'm in Los Altos now with a bunch of college buddies.
他们对我给你打工都很眼红
They're really jealous that I'm working for you.
我告诉他们办公室在顶层...
I was telling them about how the office is on the top--
你有什么爱好
What do you do for fun?
就是平常那些东西
Oh, um, you know, the usual.
打游戏  看电影
Video games. Movies.
但还是最喜欢编程
But mostly I just love to code.
你不知道我多好奇
I can't tell you how curious I am
你想让我做什么
to see what you have in mind for me.
是你来找我  莱恩
You came to me, Ryan.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我有一堆想法  我很想向你展示
I have a ton of ideas. I'd love to show them to you.
但我知道公司正全力开发2.0版
But I know the company is focused on user version 2.0 right now.
所以我准备好加入了
So I'm just ready to pitch in.
你觉得这就是我要的吗
Is that what you think I'm looking for?
好吧  有个我需要去打招呼的人来了
All right, someone just came in who I really need to speak to.
这是个派对  好好享受
Hey, it's a party. Try and have fun.
你怎么起了
What are you doing up?
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan?
不是吧
Really?
你知道你卷进什么样的情况里了吗
Do you have any idea what you're getting yourself into?
我是想学点东西...
Well, I was hoping to learn something--
我知道你现在肯定觉得自己很特别
Look, I know you must be feeling real special right about now.
乔很擅长这点  但相信我
Joe's great at that, but trust me,
他会害了你
he will burn you.
我知道我该早点告诉你此事
Look, I know I should have probably talked to you about it--
他是这么对我  戈登也是
He did it to me. He did it to Gordon.
甚至唐娜  全世界最好的女人
Even Donna, the nicest woman on the planet,
也不再跟他说话了
esn't speak to him anymore.
你觉得你会有什么不同吗
You think you're gonna be any different?
我不知道  卡梅伦
I don't know, Cameron.
我理解
Listen, I get it.
真的  我懂
Really, I do.
我愿意放过你一次
And I'm willing to give you a pass just this once.
回穆特尼
Come back to Mutiny.
干点切实的事
Be a part of something real.
我看其他人不会接受我回去的
I don't even think the guys would have me back.
如果我让他们接受  他们就得接受
Well, the guys will deal if I tell them to.
你的决定是
What do you say?
好吧
Okay.
你做了个非常愚蠢的决定
You just made a really dumb call.
我告诉她你不在家  她不肯走
I told her you weren't home. She wouldn't leave.
她等了差不多一个小时
She was here for like an hour
就干瞪眼
just staring.
老兄  你去哪了
Dude, where've you been?
我喝醉了  在乔家里昏睡过去了
I got hammered and passed out at Joe's.
好玩吗
Hey, was that fun?
我不清楚那算是什么
I don't know what the hell it was.
那明显没道理
Okay, that makes absolutely zero sense.
我们认为很有道理
Well, we thought it made a lot of sense.
你们是公司的头
Well, you guys are the heads of the company.
当然是该由你们
Of course you should be the ones
去把报价拿给跳蚤市场
to bring the offer over to SwapMeet.
戈登  这就是走个过场
Gordon, it's a formality.
博斯去就好了
Bos can do it.
这不是走过场  这事关别人的看法
It's not a formality. It's about perception.
你们要收购的人
And the people that you're buying,
特别是他们还要来这里工作
especially since they're coming to work here,
得把你和唐娜当做负责人
need to view you and Donna as the ones in charge.
戈登  我们已经见过他们无数次了
Gordon, we've already met with them a gazillion times, okay?
我们一起吃午餐  喝酒  他们知道我们是头儿
We've had lunch. We've had drinks. They know we're in charge.
要是照我的法子来  他们就把磁盘寄给我们
God, if I had it my way, they'd just send us the disks
一切就搞定了
and we could call it a day.
就是去送个信封
Okay, look, it's dropping off an envelope.
你不介意去做吧
You don't mind doing it, do you?
你还能更轻描淡写一点吗
Do you want to make it sound any less important?
-我很乐于这么做  -谢谢
- I would be happy to do it. - Thank you.
就因为她拉不下架子  整个公司
Okay, so the whole company is gonna bend over backwards
就要顺着她吗
because she can't get over herself.
不  我也觉得我们不该去
No, I don't think it's a good idea for us to go either.
公司领导不该亲自处理最初报价
The heads of the company don't tender the initial offer.
我们等回价  然后开始谈判后
We wait for the counter and only get involved
再进行干预
when the real negotiations begin.
这才能告诉他们  谁才是头儿
That's how you show them who's in charge.
好吧
Mm, okay.
好  下一项
Okay, up next,
背景图像处理的速度如何了
how are we doing on the speed of the background graphics?
以2400波特肯定无法控制在半秒之下
Well, we'll never get under half a second at 2,400 baud.
我们要用霍夫曼编码
We're gonna need to use Huffman,
或者用更好的LZ压缩算法
or even better, Lempel-Ziv compressions
这样就不用发送所有的字节
so we're not sending all the bits through.
我们怎么还要对信息理论
Okay, since when are we doing a graduate seminar
进行学术探讨了  我们的人做不到的
on information theory? Our guys can't handle that.
不  不发送所有的字节是个很聪明的办法
No, no, no. That's smart not sending all the bits through.
我们在用户已有的
We preload the most common backgrounds
磁盘上预载普通背景
on the diskettes users already have
然后只发出产品目录就行
and just send the catalog numbers.
好  只要把索引发到场景里
Okay, so just send the index to the scene.
那不错  我明白了
Okay, that's good. I see that.
这不错吧  不用复杂的编程
That's good, right? No complex coding.
这样的话图片数量有限
Well, you'll have a limited set of images
用户每次等来等去只会等来同样的图片
and the user will get tired of waiting for the same-old same-old,
但是如果你们想这样做  那也好
but, yeah, it's great if that's what you guys want to do. Great.
-很好  -好啊
- Great. - Great.
那我们就预载数据  谢谢
So we will preload the data. Thank you.
现在进入我原以为会是本次会议
And now for what I thought was going to be
唯一不愉快的议题
the only unpleasant topic for this meeting--
显然我错了
evidently I was wrong--
找人代替莱恩
replacing Ryan.
今早我去过他家了
Oh, I went by his house this morning.
他不愿意回来
He is not open to coming back.
怎么了
What?
你没伤害他吧
You didn't harm him in any way, did you?
没  我走时他还好好的
No, he was fine when I left.
他是个白痴  但他还能走
I mean, he's a moron, but he was ambulatory.
我希望你今晚能在那个班上物色下人选
You know, I want you looking for people at that class tonight.
天啊
Oh, God.
我要替你去吃午餐了
Hey, look, I'm already covering for you at this lunch.
你就别抱怨被下一代编码人才
And don't complain about being asked for by name
指名道姓地请去了
by the next generation of coding talent.
你该感到荣幸
You should be very flattered.
就算我找到了  也得好久才能赶上进度
Even if I find someone, it's gonna take forever to catch them up.
莱恩真的明白领域编码的精髓
Ryan really understood the guts of the neighborhood code.
如果要把跳蚤市场建在它边上
And if we're gonna build out SwapMeet alongside it,
我们就需要个真正懂行的人
we need someone who really gets it.
那是谁写的这部分的原始代码
Well, uh, who wrote the original code for that section?
-汤姆  -很好  汤姆是哪个
- Tom did. - Great, which one is Tom?
他不在这里了  他没和我们一起来
None of them. He didn't make the trip.
-为什么  -他就是没来
- Why not? - He just didn't.
-是因为钱的原因还是  -不是
- Okay, was it a money thing or... - No.
-那我们把他请回来  -不行
- Well, then get him back. - No.
如果不能把莱恩找回来
If you can't get Ryan,
去找写原始代码的程序员才最合理啊
getting the programmer who originated the code makes the most sense.
听着  戈登  我说了不行
Look, Gordon, I said no.
我们能不说他了吗
Can we just drop it, please?
如果没人听我的意见
Why am I even in this meeting
为什么还要我参加这个会议
if no one's gonna listen to a word I have to say?
我们在听  只是我们意见不同
We are listening. We're simply disagreeing.
不  唐娜  是你的意见不同
No, Donna, you're disagreeing.
因为你在对一些
Because you are opining on subjects
你并不了解的事发表意见
about which you do not have all the information.
我的意见是针对我完全了解的事
I am opining on subjects on which I am fully informed.
不  戈登  你真的不了解
No, Gordon, you really aren't.
你去做别的事的时候发生了很多事
A lot happened while you were off doing other things.
该死的  唐娜
Oh, damn it, Donna.
我就上过她一次  天啊
You know what? I screwed her once, okay? Jesus.
我出去一下
Excuse me.
你是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
拜托  好像卡梅伦不知道一样
Please, like Cameron doesn't already know.
家里的墙壁那么薄
The walls in our place are so goddamn thin,
我去拉屎她都听得一清二楚
she can hear it every time I take a shit.
我请你来开会  你就是这个样子吗
I invite you to a meeting and this is the way you behave?
你怎么回事
What is wrong with you?
我受够了  不想再受罚了
I am sick and tired of being punished.
好吗  我同意搬家  我买了主机
Okay? I agreed to the move. I bought the mainframe.
我又修好了主机  我让她和我们一起住
I fixed the mainframe. I've let her live with us.
你提出的一切要求  我都照做了
Everything I've been asked to do, I've done.
我反驳你是因为汤姆是卡梅伦前男友
I shut you down because Tom is Cameron's ex-boyfriend.
那又怎样
So what?
这显然是个敏感话题
So it's obviously a sensitive subject
我是想让你不再谈论这个话题
and I was trying to steer you away from it.
所以你觉得我劈腿是个不错的话题
So you thought my infidelity would be a wonderful topic?
是你先提起的
You brought that up.
我去做别的事的时候
While I was off doing other things.
好像这屋里的人都不懂似的
Like everybody in this room doesn't know what that means.
-我指的是主机的事  -才不是呢
- I was talking about the mainframe. - No, you weren't.
你指的不是主机  别跟我装
No, you weren't and don't pretend that you were.
这事一直阴魂不散  唐娜
It's always there, Donna.
每次我看着你  你从没放过它
Every time I look at you, it's always there.
我们不该在这儿讨论这事
This is not something to discuss here.
回家再说
We'll talk about it at home.
有什么区别吗
What's the difference?
有人吗
Hello?
从以太向你问好
Greetings from the ether.
有人吗
Is anybody there?
我在  听得到吗
I'm right here. Can you hear me?
我在  这里是KC4L  完毕
I'm right here. This is KC4L, over.
你好
Hello?
我在  能听到吗
I'm right here. Can you hear me?
这边请
Right this way.
第一次在我们这儿就餐吗
First time dining with us?
不是  是倒好了
No. I wish.
-你好  -不用起来
- Oh, hello there. - No, don't get up.
抱歉
Sorry.
卡梅伦呢
Where's Cameron?
她在为今晚的客座演讲准备
Oh, she is preparing a guest lecture she is giving tonight.
她很遗憾不能抽身前来
She's so sorry that she couldn't make it.
我们只好自己吃了
We'll have to soldier on without her.
需要喝点什么吗
May I get you something from the bar?
请给我一杯金汤力
You know what? I will have a gin and tonic, please.
-好的  -谢谢
- Very well. - Thank you.
好选择
Nice choice.
你又是为什么呢
And what's your excuse?
我喜欢午餐时喝酒罢了
I just like drinking at lunch.
跳蚤市场的正式报价是今天吗
So, the official SwapMeet offer is happening today?
是的  今天下午就交给约翰·博斯沃思了
Yes, John Bosworth is taking it over later this afternoon.
-太激动了  -是啊
- Exciting. - Yeah.
他会跟你和卡梅伦一起去吗
Will he go over with you and Cameron?
不  他是我们的代理人
No, he's our advance man.
他会打理好一切的
He's taking care of it.
-女士们  可以点餐了  -老样子  杰森
- Whenever the ladies are ready. - The usual, Jason.
烤炙鸡块
Chicken paillard.
很脆薄  但依然多汁
It's thin, crispy, and somehow still juicy.
不知他们是怎么做到的
I don't know how they do it.
我就来一份...
Uh, you know, I will try the...
意大利蘑菇饭吧
mushroom ris-- risotto.
你还戴着戒指呢
You still wear your ring, huh?
工作所需
For work.
男人好像不明白女人可以单身逍遥
Men can't seem to handle the idea that sexual availability
还具备商业头脑
and business acumen can exist in the same body.
这可以省去不少麻烦
It simplifies things.
你说约翰·博斯沃思是你们的代理人
So when you say John Bosworth is your advance man,
是什么意思
what exactly do you mean?
干什么呢
Whatcha doing?
我在跟布伦特研究2.0版
Oh, I'm just working on 2.0 with Brent.
我觉得这事该全员出动
I figured it was all hands on deck,
所以就来帮忙
so I would jump in and help out.
不必  我都有布伦特了
Don't do that. I've already got a Brent.
我雇你不是干那个的
That's not what I hired you for.
等等
Excuse me.
等等我
Excuse me. Wait.
那你为什么雇我
Hey, man, why did you hire me, then?
我也开始觉得疑惑了
I'm beginning to wonder that myself.
我就是...
You know, I just--
我当时并不知道会是这个情况
I didn't know what I was getting myself into.
我是那么想修复一切
You know, and I wanted to fix things so bad,
但是
but, I don't know,
她似乎并不想要我
she just doesn't seem to want me there.
她虽然嘴上说想
I mean, she says she does,
但她只是觉得我想听到那话
but that's what she thinks I want to hear.
等等
Oh, wait.
唐娜
Donna?
我老婆回来了  KC4L下线
That's my wife. This is KC4L signing off.
唐娜
Hey, Donna.
无线电可算调好了
I, uh, finally got the ham working.
你知道我是打算搬出去的吧
You know I was always planning on moving out, right?
这对我来说也并不是理想的安排
Like, this is not exactly an ideal setup for me either.
我也不喜欢听你拉屎
It's not like I like listening to you take a dump.
而且  唐娜从没跟我提过
You know, just for the record, Donna never said anything to me
你们之间的问题
about whatever problems you guys were having.
她绝不会那么做的
She would never do that.
我拿到了通关证
I have the letters of transit.
一份重要文件
A very important document.
跳蚤市场的报价
It's the SwapMeet offer.
祝你好运  先生
And Godspeed to you, sir.
午餐吃的怎么样
How was lunch?
非常愉快
Extremely delightful.
我吃了炖饭
I had risotto,
就是米饭  但别有风味
which is rice, but not.
你还吃什么了
What else did you have?
我喝了几杯...好几杯金汤力
I had a few-- several gin and tonics.
-你没事吧  -我很好
- You okay? - Yes, I'm great.
挺好
Fine.
我前妻以前飞长途
You know, my ex worked those long-haul flights
我出个差一去就半个月
and I was away on business half the month.
我们几乎都不在一起
We barely spent any time together.
但还是能气得对方跳脚
Still managed to get on each other's last nerve.
真不知道你和戈登怎么做到的
I don't know how you and Gordon do it.
看来做得并不很好
Well, apparently, not so well.
你丈夫是挺难搞
I think your husband's all kind of tricky,
但我知道他在乎你
but, by God, I know he cares.
隔着老远就能感觉出来
I can feel it from 50 paces.
还有很多男人干过更糟的事呢  唐娜
There are men out there who've done a lot worse, Donna.
是啊
Yeah.
但这也不算什么好事
But it's hard to turn that into good news.
我要你来参加这次会议
I want you to come to this meeting.
-现在吗  -是的
- Right now? - Right now.
你就是约翰·博斯沃思吧
You must be John Bosworth.
黛安·古德  我今天下午给你打支援
Diane Gould. I'll be your backup this afternoon.
认识你很高兴
Oh, pleasure to meet you.
不知道我还需要人支援
Didn't know I needed backup.
你当然不需要
Well, you don't, of course.
只是我知道你会来
I just knew you'd be here and
觉得我们正好可以认识一下
I thought it would be a nice way for us to meet.
好啊
Sure.
好安静
Seems a little quiet.
我也发现了
Yeah, I noticed that.
停车场也很空
And the parking lot seemed empty.
我也发现了
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
或许我们该去转转
Maybe we should get a tour.
我要把我辛苦挣来的60万给他们
We're giving them 600,000 of my hard-earned dollars
你们公司也要割肉
and a piece of your company.
我们总该有权看看吧
That earns us a poke around.
道格·谢雷登  认识你很高兴
Doug Sheridan. So nice to meet you.
这是我合伙人  克雷格·鲍什
This is my partner Craig Bausch.
你好  我是约翰·博斯沃思
Craig, John Bosworth.
很高兴终于把脸跟名字对上了
Nice to finally put some faces to the names.
这是黛安·古德  我们的合作伙伴
This here is Diane Gould, our partner.
当然  很高兴终于见到你了
Of course. Pleasure to finally meet you.
送份报价这么大阵势
This is quite the delivery committee.
既然我们来了  正好想到处看看
While we're here, we thought we should have a look around.
当然
Oh, of course.
没问题
Sure.
欢迎
Welcome.
我们昨晚熬夜熬到很晚
We pulled a pretty epic all-nighter last night,
所以现在人手很少
so we're kind of down to bare bones.
但能大致了解这里的情况
But you should be able to get a sense of the place.
我知道各位投资人
I know I speak for all the investors
都跟我一样
when I say how delighted we are
对个人用户群的增长非常满意
with the growth of the individual user base.
难喝死了
That tastes terrible.
真的...
I mean, that tastes just like...
我们最初虽然没预料到
Look, we may not have seen it at the start,
但人们的反响说明一切
but the people have spoken
你真的是
and you truly are
我们一直看好的思想领袖
the thought leader that we always knew you were.
2.0版
So 2.0.
我们什么时候发布
When are we doing this?
生产部只需几个月就可以准备发货
Well, production can have disks ready to ship in a matter of months.
问题是  收费是
The question is, is it better
从年初就开始
to start charging at the beginning of the year?
还是九月开始
Or do we flip the switch in September
希望收费单
and hope that the charges get
跟返校开销混在一起不被发现
lost in the list of back-to-school expenses?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
你觉得我们该什么时候
When do you think we should
开始对新用户版收费
start charging for the new user version?
我...
Well, I--
我以为你不打算收费呢
I mean, I thought you weren't going to charge.
等等
Hold on, I'm--
抱歉  你叫什么来着
I'm sorry, what's your name again?
-莱恩  -对了
- Ryan. - Ryan, right.
我们当然要收费的
Of course we're gonna charge.
培养用户群不就是
I mean, what's the point of developing a user base
为了最终把他们变成付钱的客户吗
if we don't turn them into paying customers at some point?
我认为  这事越早越好
And my gut is telling me sooner rather than later.
真意外
What a surprise.
我看到流金子的龙头  就想打开它
I see a spigot and I want to turn it on.
焦点小组调查表明
The focus groups we've done indicate
我们将因收费失去30%到40%的用户
we'll be losing 30-40% of our users whenever we do it.
只看你想
It's just a matter of how
在之前把用户群扩展到什么地步了
big you want to grow the base beforehand.
遗憾的是
And, unfortunately,
人们会恨你一阵的
people are going to hate you for a little while.
抱歉  没办法
Sorry, couldn't be helped.
我早就不在乎人们怎么想我了
Well, it's been a long time since I cared what people thought about me.
我认为
My gut says...
九月更好
September.
零售价是多少
What's our price point?
如果能控制在15美元大关以下
If we can stay below the $15 threshold,
用户似乎愿意付费
consumers seem willing to shine it on.
好高啊  不能控制在10美元以下吗
Oof, that sounds awfully high. Can't we keep it under 10?
不  这种一次性的年费
No, the fact is for a one-time annual expense of this kind--
14.95元呗
$14.95.
是啊  这个好
Yes. That.
就这个
That right there. That--
我同意  很好
that has my vote. Yes, please.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
嗯
Yeah, I-I guess
14.95元挺不错的
$14.95 sounds good.
既然莱恩都同意了
Well, if Ryan's on board, huh?
那就这样了
So that's it.
到九月  我们就收费  14.95美元
Come September, we start charging $14.95.
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah, of course.
我知道这不好受
Look, I know it tastes bad,
但这么做是对的
but this is the right move.
我保证
I promise you, all right?
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
怎么了
What is it?
我
Hey, I--
我想说  尽管雇佣代码的原始编写者
I just wanted to say that even though it does make perfect sense
是合理的选择
to hire the person who wrote that code,
但我并不知道你跟他的事
I didn't realize that that was someone that you had a thing with.
如果我今天早些时候显得不近人情
So if I seemed insensitive earlier today,
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧
Okay.
那个...代码是我和汤姆一起写的
And just-- Tom and I wrote that code together.
就是想告诉你一声
Just, you know, FYI.
并不是他一个人干的
It wasn't all him.
好
Okay.
希望我没有让你觉得
And I hope I didn't make you feel
你住在这里是我们一切问题的根源
like you living here is the cause of all of our problems.
你不会开始跟我说你妻子的事吧
You're not gonna start talking to me about your wife, are you?
不会
No, I'm not.
因为...我真心觉得我没法面对这个
Just 'cause I really-- I don't think I can handle that.
听着  我依然觉得
Look, I still don't think
我们不该住在一个屋檐下
that we should all be living under the same roof,
但显然  还有其他的问题
but obviously there's something else going on.
我只想说这个
That's all I wanted to say.
你们什么时候搬出去呢
So when are you guys moving out?
天呐  你把全家的杯子都拿进来了啊
Jesus, you got every goddamn mug in the house in here.
才没有
No, I don't.
好吧  今晚好运
All right. Hey, good luck tonight.
你也是
You, too.
我真不懂风怎么吹进烛台球场的
I just don't understand how the wind gets into Candlestick.
这不是有墙的吗
I mean, there are walls.
风是巨人队的球迷  想干啥干啥
Wind's a Giants fan. It does what it needs to do.
不比阿灵顿的蒸笼强多了
It beats the hell out of sweating bullets in Arlington.
所以我是休斯顿球迷
Yeah, well, that's why I'm a Houston fan.
空调吹得像天堂
Air conditioning like God intended it.
诺兰·莱恩把
Where was God when Nolan Ryan
威尔·克拉克晾在一边时上帝在哪呢
left that one hanging for Will Clark the other day?
不去接一下吗
You want to get that?
没事
No, it's fine.
这事更重要
This is more important.
多谢你们这么重视
Yeah, hey, we appreciate the extra attention,
但你们没有接待员吗
but don't you fellas have a receptionist?
当然有  她去吃午饭了
Of course we do. She's at lunch.
-吃晚了  -我们常跟东岸做生意
- Late lunch. - We do a lot of business with the East Coast.
我们常会午餐时间工作
So we work through lunch a lot and then we,
之后再吃
you know, have it later.
谁去接下电话
Can somebody answer the goddamn phone?
大家昨晚都累坏了
Everybody's really spent from last night.
真是筋疲力尽
It was a real ball-breaker.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧
Sure.
你这是干什么
What'd you do that for?
我不喜欢这个
Oh, I'm not comfortable with it.
这数字是我们依据
No, it was a figure that was arrived at
不怎么及时的信息得出的
when we were operating with less than current information.
我们公司的价值在于我们的知识产权
The value of our company is in our intellectual property,
以及忠实的用户  而不在办公室里
our loyal customers, it's not out there.
可不是嘛  走吧
No, it sure as hell isn't. Come on.
这是要去哪
Where are you going?
我们得重新考虑
Oh, we need to reassess.
博斯沃思先生  我保证  你要买下的公司
Mr. Bosworth, I assure you the company you're bidding on
是其自身的精简版
is a lean, mean version of itself.
绝对是够精简  也就值40万吧
Oh, I'd say it's a lean, mean version worth about 400K.
40万是个不错的起价
400,000 sounds like a good place to start.
不  是终价才对  孩子
No, it sounds like a good place to finish, son.
如果你们找得到
If you can find someone willing
愿给35万以上的  就去找他们吧
to pay north of 350, you should go for it.
-等等  他说40的  -抱歉  我的错
- Wait, he just said 400. - Oh, I'm sorry. My mistake.
32.5万  如何
325, how's that sound?
我们替你省了25万
We just saved you $250,000.
你怎么不开心点
I'd think you'd be happier.
我很开心
I am happy, very.
我就是有点意外
I'm just a little surprised
你完全没按计划的来
by how completely off-book you went.
我以为这次就是寒暄一番就成交了
I thought this was supposed to be handshakes and how do you dos.
看到机会就该抓住嘛
You see an opportunity, you take it.
乐趣就在此
That's the sport of it.
也可能是另一种结果
It could have gone the other way.
但并不是
But it didn't.
麦克米伦先生
Mr. MacMillan?
我想说
Uh, I just wanted to say that--
我觉得你不该对用户版收费
that I don't think you should charge for the user version.
你怎么不在会上说
Why didn't you say that in the meeting?
我来这里才一周
I've been here for, what, a week
你就让我参加高级员工会议
and you plunk me down in some senior staff meeting.
我还能说什么  当然是随声附和了
What was I supposed to say? I just agreed with everyone else.
但是我不该那样  因为我并不是那么想的
But that's not right because it's not what I think.
很遗憾你在会上发懵了
I'm sorry you couldn't keep up in the meeting.
你向人们承诺你不会收钱的
You made a promise to people that you wouldn't charge them.
我没说今后也不收
I didn't promise that I wouldn't ever charge them.
你就是说了
Of course you did.
你说摆脱恐惧是种权利
You said freedom from fear is a right
人们不该为此付钱
and you shouldn't have to pay for it.
在完美世界里  确实如此
And in a perfect world that would be true,
但我们生活的世界并非如此
but it's not the world we live in.
-那你为什么那么说  -因为我是那么想的
- Then why'd you say it? - Because I believe it.
但我有董事会和投资者
But I've got a board and investors
还有我需要听命于的人
and I've got people to answer to.
但你会毁了这个产品
But you're ruining the product.
我就是产品本身
I am the product.
我知道
I know.
不  我是奥斯汀理工大学的
No, I was at Austin Tech.
我没毕业  就开始工作了
I never really finished, but then I started working
后来就没时间回去完成学业了
and there was just no real time to go back.
再次感谢你来
Thanks again for coming.
嗯
Yeah.
可以开始了
Feel free to start.
这次不吻我了吗
What, no kiss this time?
你想怎么样
What do you want?
你要说我是个烂人吗  说吧
You gonna tell me I'm a horrible person? Go ahead.
我也有权这么说
I'd be well within my rights to want that.
但我真心想说的
What I'd really like to say is--
是谢谢你
is thank you.
是吗
Really?
谢什么
For what?
一切吧
Everything, I guess.
如果不是你把一切烧成了灰
How could I have risen from the ashes
我又怎么能涅槃重生
if you hadn't burned it all to the ground?
所以你挖走了我最好的程序员吗
Is that why you stole my best coder?
莱恩吗  得了
Who, Ryan? Come on.
硅谷里莱恩这种人多得是
The Valley is crawling with Ryans.
才不是  他是很有才的
No, actually, he's incredibly talented.
你想要回他吗
Do you want him back?
你来干什么  你跟踪我来的吗
What are you doing here? Did you follow me here?
不  卡梅  我没那个时间
No, Cam, I don't have time to follow you.
我
I'm a--
是这儿的学生
I'm a student.
有什么好笑的
Why is that funny?
因为你在撒谎
Because it's a lie.
或许我是厌倦了别人说我
Well, maybe I got tired of being told
只是个不会代码的推销员
I was just a salesman who couldn't code.
好吧
Okay.
我...
I--
天呐  我不知道你在玩什么扮装游戏
God, I don't know what kind of dress-up game you're playing,
但你真是个学生
but, yes, you're a student.
我可能永远不会精于这个
I might not ever be great at it, but...
但我也是能学的
I'm not unteachable.
乔
Joe,
我知道你这副
I know you got this whole
谦逊禅师的样子挺受欢迎
humble Zen master thing working for you,
但得了
but come on.
省省吧
Save it.
我才不会信呢
I'm not buying it.
你不非得信  卡梅
You don't have to buy it, Cam.
你没听说吗
Haven't you heard?
我要免费送出我的产品
I'm giving it away for free.
卡梅
Cam.
他们昨晚怎么样
How were they last night?
我没看到他们
I didn't see them.
我回到家时他们已经回房了
They were in their room when I got home
早上我走时他们已经走了
and gone before I left this morning.
挺安静的
It was quiet.
那并不总是个好兆头
Yeah, that's not always a good sign.
总比大吼大叫强
Well, it's better than screaming.
我听过让人恨不得大叫的安静
I've heard quiet make you beg for screaming.
放好了
Put that there.
我想为我昨天的爆发道歉
I want to apologize for my outburst yesterday.
非常不合适
It was totally inappropriate.
也不该发生那种事
And it shouldn't have happened.
如果我让谁不舒服了
So if I made anyone feel uncomfortable,
那么很抱歉
then I'm sorry.
这段话才让我不舒服呢
Well, that little speech made me very uncomfortable.
-开玩笑的  -就当没那回事
- I'm kidding. - It never happened.
-得了  -怎么
- Come on. - What?
-就是有那回事嘛  -就是个说法
- It so clearly did. - It's a thing you say.
好了  我们不用再说那件事了
Okay, look, we don't have to discuss this ad nauseam,
我们只是觉得什么都不说也不好
but we thought saying nothing seemed equally stupid.
所以决定至少说点什么
So we're saying something.
我们知道把婚姻关系带到工作中来
We are aware that bringing a marriage into the workplace
是很复杂的  我们在尽力了  好吗
is complicated and we're doing the best we can, okay?
我们继续工作吧
Now, can we try to get back to where we were?
好的
Okay, great.
莱恩的空缺
The big Ryan-shaped hole.
你昨晚找到合适人选了吗
Did you find any prospects last night?
没有  但我决定不用雇其他人了
No, but I decided we don't need anyone.
-当然用了  -不用
- Of course we do. - No.
我来做不就行了
Not if I do it.
这好吗  我觉得你已经很忙了
Oh, I don't know. I feel like you're already spread pretty thin.
不  他说得对  找原本编写代码的人
No, he was right. Getting the person who originated the code
是最合理的  那就是我
makes the most sense. That's me.
但你该找点帮手啊
Well, but you should have some help.
我们刚买了家公司  找他们来帮忙呗
We just bought a company. Maybe one of them can help.
不  我还得跟他们解释一切
No! Look, I'd just have to explain everything to them.
那样我事倍功半
It makes double the work for me.
好吧  如果你觉得你能行的话
All right, if you think you can handle it.
我能行
Yes, I can.
好  我们接到电话
Okay, so we got a call--
不是吧  这就进入下一话题了
You got to be kidding me. You're moving on?
是啊  你有什么想说的吗
Yes. Did you have something you wanted to say?
没有  继续吧  是你们的会议
No. No, no, go ahead. It's your meeting.
-我们接到电话  -她不能自己做
- We got a call-- - She can't do it herself.
这家公司本就在花三分之一的时间等她了
The company spends a third of its time waiting for her as it is.
他没说错  你把工作分出去点有好处
He's not wrong. You could do a bit more delegating.
我有分派  我只是觉得
I do, just not when it's
这件事是我们的基础
something that I think is truly foundational.
你觉得什么事都是我们的基础
But you think that everything is foundational.
既然她说她能做到  她就能做到
Look, if she says she can handle it, she can handle it.
天呐  天呐  天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
戈登  你究竟什么意思
Gordon, what is your argument?
你这样会毁了公司的  老是这样...
You're just sinking the company by taking on all these--
-她才没有毁什么  -我们能不能说主题
- No, she's not sinking anything. - Can we please just focus?
收拾你的东西
I want you to pack up your stuff.
明天开始  我们在我家工作
Starting tomorrow, we'll be working out of my place.
如果2.0版我们还想不收费
If we're not charging for 2.0,
就得找个新的收入源
we've got to find a new income stream.
别笑  我们可能会失败
Don't smile. We might fail.